http://www.bando.com/pages/privacy-policy

Effective Date: 1/14/2020
We Are Committed to Helping You Make the Most of Your Time Online Within a Trusted Environment.
Ban.do (“We,” “Our,” or “Us”)  respect your privacy and are letting you know about Our online privacy policies. This Privacy Policy discloses how We collect, protect, use, and share information gathered about you on www.bando.com and webpages sharing the same domain (the “Site”). We hope that this disclosure will help increase your confidence in Our site and enhance your experience on the internet.  Your use of the Site indicates your acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy and Our Terms of Use.  Furthermore, for Site visitors located in the European Union, please see Our EU Privacy Policy.
Types of Information We Collect and How We Collect It
The majority of the product and service information posted on Our Site is offered without Our collecting any personally identifiable information from you. You can navigate the Site and view much of Our content without providing personal information to Us.
Information You Provide
There are a few activities on Our Site where the collection of personally identifiable information is necessary. Those activities include things like entering a contest or sweepstakes, giveaway, making a purchase, requesting a catalog, newsletter or other information, registering on Our Site, filling out a survey or questionnaire, or contacting us. We do not market to, seek to solicit information from, or knowingly collect information from children under 13. When We collect personally identifiable information, you will know because you will have to provide that information to us. For most activities, We collect only your name, e-mail address, street address, zip code  , birth date   and any other relevant information necessary to complete your requests. For example, when you make a purchase, we also collect your billing address, your phone number, and credit card information. If you visit Our pages on social media sites such as Facebook, Pinterest, and Twitter, we may collect both personally-identifiable and non-personally-identifiable information.  For example, if you ask a customer service question through our Facebook page, we will receive your username along with your question and will use that information to respond to your question.  We will store personally identifiable information so long as We have a legitimate business purpose to do so in accordance with applicable law.   We will continue to store anonymous or anonymized information, such as Site visits, in order to improve Our services.
We do not market to, seek to solicit information from, or knowingly collect information from children under 13 nor is the Site is not intended for use by children.   Consistent with the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), if We learn that We have received any information directly from a child under age 13 without first receiving his or her parent's verified consent, We will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian if known) to inform the child that he or she cannot use the Site and subsequently We will delete information associated with the child.
Information Collected from You with Technology
Our Site collects some information about you using technology, so it may not be readily apparent to you that it is being collected. For instance, when you visit Our Site, We automatically collect certain non-personally identifiable information from your browser, such as your Internet service provider's address, the web page from which you came, and a record of your activity on Our Site. This information is not personally identifiable. If you visit Our Site on a mobile device, We collect information about the device, including the operating system and your location. Our Site uses information collected through technology to make Our Site more interesting and useful to you, help Us with usability on Our Site to make your life easier, help Us to ensure that Our Site works properly on your device, and help Us generally improve the content and layout of Our Site, notify you about updates to Our Site, and contact you for marketing purposes.
Description of Cookies, Tracking Pixels and Other Technologies and How We Use Them
Cookies are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing the website. These pieces of information allow the websites to remember important information that will make your use of those sites easier and more helpful. Our Site and other websites use cookies and other similar technologies, including tracking pixels and clear GIFs, for a variety of purposes. They enable Us to identify your device when you move between different websites and applications so that We can help you find products you might be most interested in or serve targeted advertising and marketing offers to you.
As a result of your accessing Our Site, We may use third party cookies and other technologies and may receive information about your browsing and buying activity on Our Site. Some of this information will be used to market our products to you on third-party websites.
We contract with one or more third-party service partners to provide Us with a data collection and reporting service. When you access Our Site, a third-party service partner may use cookies and other technologies on Our behalf and may receive information about your browsing and buying activity on Our Site. Such data collection may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis, and We may share this aggregated data with Our affiliates, agents, and business partners, such as Google Analytics. This aggregate information does not identify you personally. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe Our market to current and prospective business partners, and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer, or Edge) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many of Our features that make your web experience more efficient.
The Type of Security We Provide
The importance of security for all personally identifiable information associated with Our users is of utmost concern to us. We take technical, contractual, administrative, and physical security steps to protect all visitors' information. We use secure socket layer (SSL) encryption across Our Site to protect your information.  However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure.  As such, We cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personal information.
There are some things that you can do to help protect the security of your information as well. For instance, never give out your password, since this is what is used to access all of your account information. Also, remember to sign out of your account and close your browser window when you finish surfing the web so that other people using the same computer won't have access to your information.  You should use caution when using public Wi-Fi, which can make your personal information available to others if not properly secured.
How We Use the Personally Identifiable Information that We Collect
We use personally identifiable information in a limited number of ways. We use the information to complete transactions. For instance, if you contact Us for help, We will use the information to contact you. If you place an order, We use your information to ship those goods to you. We use information collected to notify you if you've won a game or contest. Information We collect is also used to send you e-mail updates or news, information on products and services, discounts, upcoming events and newsletters about Our brand(s) and other information we think you will find valuable, periodic mailings, and in some instances telephone contact.
Who We Share Your Information With
Sometimes we use third-party companies (“Service Providers”) to help Us target advertising or to market or remarket products you were interested in from Our Site, or to facilitate order processing and fulfillment. In those instances, We share your information with them to target advertising, deliver products, assist Us in collecting and managing customer information, fulfill promotions and/orders and/or communicate with you.
These Service Providers include:
Shopify – We use Shopify to facilitate online & retail orders. By using Our Site you agree to Shopify’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Klaviyo – We use Klaviyo to provide email marketing services. By using Our Site you agree to Klaviyo’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Deposco – We use Deposco facilitate order fulfillment. By using Our Site you agree to Deposco’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Zapier – We use to transfer data between cloud systems. By using Our Site you agree to Zapier’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Formstack – We use for marketing forms and surveys. By using Our Site forms and survey’s you agree to Formstack’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Yotpo – We use for user contributed product reviews. By providing a customer review Our Site you agree to Yotpo’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Swell – We use for our rewards and referral programs. By creating an account on our site or participating in our referral program, you agree to Swell’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Google Analytics – We use Google for website metrics. By using Our Site you agree to Google’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Attentive – We use Attentive for SMS messaging. By subscribing to receive texts from ban.do, you agree to Attentive’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Pushowl – We use Pushowl for browser push notifications. By opting in to receive browser push notifications, you agree to Pushowl’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Handshake – We use Handshake to collect orders at trade shows. By ordering from Us at a trade show you agree to Handshake’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Returnly – We use Returnly to facilitate customer returns. By placing an order on our site you agree to Returnly’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Returnly – We use Returnly to facilitate customer returns. By placing an order on our site you agree to Returnly’s collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
Eventbrite – We use Eventbrite to manage RSVPs and ticket sales for our events. By RSVPing or purchasing a ticket, you agree to Eventbrite's collection of data under its Privacy Policy.
UPS, FedEx, USPS, and other trusted couriers and carriers – Customer mailing address and contact information will be provided to outside entities as necessary to fulfill and deliver orders.
Various advertisers – We use Facebook, Instagram, Google, Amazon, Bing and other advertising providers to provide advertising services for Us and Our Site. See below on how you can opt-out of tracking by these advertisers.
Some of these companies are given access to some or all of the information you provide Us, and some may use cookies or other tracking technologies on Our behalf. These companies are restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping Us to target advertising or to deliver or provide you with Our products.
Ban.do uses targeted advertising services provided by companies such as Facebook, Google, and Amazon. These services are intended to deliver advertisements that you are likely to be interested in, based on your recent browsing. Those services use technical means such as cookies and pixel tags to collect data as described in their privacy notices in order to help provide ads that are more relevant to you. As pertinent to Our Site, they collect data about your browsing activity, such as which pages you visited and when; technical information about your device and browser such as your device's IP address, device type and unique identifier; information about what ads have been served to you and whether you interacted with the ad; and data from third-party advertising partners such as pseudonymous identifiers to help deliver ads to you and recognize you across browsers and devices. The third-party vendors offer ways to opt out of tracking and that information can be found on their respective websites.  You may also opt out of targeted ads from specific third-party vendors by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Opt-Out page at http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/
On occasion, We offer promotions — such as giveaways — in conjunction with a sponsor. We may share your information with the sponsors if they need it to send you a product or to fulfill the promotion. We may share your information with those sponsors so that they can send you other special promotions. You will know We are going to do this because We will tell you when you sign up for these kinds promotions. In addition, We will occasionally send e-mail promotions to Our users on behalf of third-party sponsors regarding lifestyle-related products or services.
We may also share information for security reasons to prevent, investigate, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of persons, violations of Our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.
Links to Other Websites and Social Media
Our Site may contain links to other websites of interest.  However, once you have used these links to leave Our Site, you should note that We do not have any control over that other website.  Therefore, We cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy.  You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Communication, engagement and actions taken through social media platforms that this Site and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.  This Site may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.
Sale of Businesses
Over the course of Our operation, it is possible that at some point We may sell some, all or certain portions of Our businesses or assets to other companies. When such an event occurs, visitor information (including personally identifiable information) may constitute a part of the transferred business assets. In the event that We sell substantially all of Our assets to another company, visitor information (including personally identifiable information) likely will be considered an asset that will be transferred to the acquiring company.
Organizations That Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Users and our Sites
We will give out personal information as required by law, to comply with a court order or subpoena, to enforce Our Terms of Service, or to protect the safety and security of users and Our Site.
Your Rights
You may request information about your personal information, to review your personal information, or that We delete your personal information. We may reject your request, as permitted by applicable law. If We reject your request, We will notify you of the reasons for the rejection.
California consumers have the right to request and receive (1) the categories of personal information We have collected about that consumer; (2) the categories of sources from which the personal information is collected; (3) the business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling personal information; (4) the categories of third parties with whom We share personal information; and (5) the specific pieces of personal information We have collected about that consumer.
We do not discriminate in any way against an individual exercising his or her rights under any relevant data privacy statute or regulation, including the California Consumer Privacy Act.
Changes to this Privacy Notice
Changes to this Privacy Notice will be posted on this page. If we make a material change to Our privacy practices, we will provide notice on the Site or by other means as required by law.
How to Contact Us
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or about ban.do generally, or to opt out of promotional contacts, you may contact Us by email at info@bando.com, or by postal mail at:
Ban.do Designs, LLC134 Beech Bend RoadBowling Green, KY 42103
Join our email list for new product releases, endless inspiration, and 10% off your next order.
SHIPPING FROM:
united states
united kingdom
© 2020 ban.do®PRIVACY POLICY (updated Jan 14 2020) | TERMS OF USE | ACCESSIBILITY
SHIPPING FROM:
united states
united kingdom
© 2020 ban.do® | Privacy Policy (updated Jan 14 2020) | Terms of Use | Accessibility
